cfi-universal.com 2018-05-08

# Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy
CFI Euro SL takes the privacy of our Members and Project Members seriously. We are
committed to safeguarding your privacy while providing You with our high-quality platform.
Objective and Scope of This Privacy Policy
This CFI Euro Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy”) is issued by CFI Euro SL. for itself and its members
(collectively "CFI”, "We”, or "Us”) to explain the data processing practices of CFI. CFI processes
personal data in accordance with the requirements of the European Union’s Data Protection
Directive and the data protection laws and other applicable laws and regulations of the
countries in which We provide services. This Privacy Policy applies to personal data as defined
by the Data Protection Directive and national data protection laws ("Personal Data”) and to
other information that You provide to CFI. This Privacy Policy describes how We collect and
process information provided by You, your right to limit our processing of your information,
and your right to access, correct, and delete your information that We hold. Additional details
about our use of your information with respect to specific CFI services is found in the relevant
terms and conditions, which should be read together with this Privacy Policy.
Your Consent to Use Personal Data
We use your Personal Data only with your consent. You may withhold or withdraw your
consent for CFI to process your Personal Data. Certain Personal Data is required for Us to
provide services or merchandise orders to You or to meet our legal obligations, and your
withholding or withdrawal of consent to use this Personal Data may prevent CFI from
providing the services that You have registered for. Other Personal Data is not required for Us
to provide those services to You but is used by Us to provide You with better levels of service
or for marketing and communications as well as other purposes. Your consent to this use of
your Personal Data is optional. We will advise You which Personal Data You must provide and
which is optional. By using CFI’s website and platform, you consent to the collection of certain
information. See ‘How Do We Collect Information?’ below.
CFI Euro SL -Privacy Policy – Version. 1.0 – 12 May 2017

What Information Do We Collect?
The Personal Data and other information that we process varies depending on your
relationship with CFI Euro SL. Among the Personal Data and other information that We may
collect is the following:
• Name
• Residential address
• Date of birth
• National identification number
• Telephone number
• IP and MAC addresses and browser information
• Email address
• Banking details, credit or debit card information, or other information needed to process
payments to or from You
• Demographic information such as your profession, hobbies, education, gender, ethnicity,
and income. This type of information is never mandatory.
• Other identifying information
Use of Cookies
Cookies are small text files that are sent to your computer so that our websites can remember
the settings and information that you submit. That way You don’t have to re-enter them when
You re-visit a page or visit a new page on the same website. We also use cookies to measure
how You use our websites so that We can make sure that they meet your needs. You can
control whether or not your computer accepts cookies, however, refusing to accept cookies
may affect your experience using our websites. For more information about cookies, please
go to the website www.allaboutcookies.org.
CFI Euro SL -Privacy Policy – Version. 1.0 – 12 May 2017

How Do We Collect Information?
We collect Personal Data and other information from You in a variety of ways, including:
• the submission of Personal Data by You to CFI through our websites ;
• the use of cookies;
• the submission of an online order for CFI services or merchandise orders;
• the submission of a project and donation request;
• when We and You communicate by email, telephone, chat line, or otherwise; and
• provision of your Personal Data to CFI by CFI’s business partners.
CFI will not contact You by telephone or email to request information such as credit card
numbers, account numbers, passwords and pin codes. Do not open or respond to e-mails
requesting this type of information. Please contact CFI if You receive such a request.
How Do We Use Your Personal Data?
CFI processes Personal Data for a variety of purposes, including:
• to verify, process, and administer your registrations for CFI services
• to ensure a secure ordering of merchandise product process
• to maintain our commercial relationship with You
• to analyse, understand, and respond to your service needs
• to improve the products and services that We offer to You and to develop new products
and services
• to meet our legal and regulatory obligations and to protect CFI’s legal and financial
interests (including fraud detection and prevention)
CFI Euro SL -Privacy Policy – Version. 1.0 – 12 May 2017

• for the provision of services to our Members and Project Managers and compliance with
our contractual obligations to them
• to facilitate financial, accounting and administrative functions
• to send commercial and marketing communications to You about services and products
from CFI and CFI business partners that We believe may be of interest to you.
We may provide your Personal Data to governmental authorities in response to specific
requests from those authorities or as part of statistical and analytical reports. When
information is provided in statistical or analytical form, information that might specifically
identify you will not be disclosed.
How Long Do We Keep Your Personal Data?
CFI keeps your Personal Data as long as it is required for the purposes for which it was initially
collected. In certain situations, We may need to keep your Personal Data for a minimum
period to comply with legal requirements. We do not keep your Personal Data longer than
permitted by law.
Where and How Do We Store Your Personal Data?
Your Personal Data is stored by CFI on secure computer servers located in The Netherlands.
See Transfer of Personal Data to Third Parties below. All Personal Data is stored according to
industry standards. See Security below.
Third-Party Sites
CFI’s websites contain links to third-party sites owned or operated by CFI business partners or
other companies. If You use these links, You will leave CFI’s websites. This Privacy Policy does
not apply to third-party websites. You should review the privacy disclosures of those websites.
CFI Euro SL -Privacy Policy – Version. 1.0 – 12 May 2017

Transfer of Personal Data to Third Parties
CFI may transfer your Personal Data to third parties as permitted by this Privacy Policy and
applicable law. CFI transfers Personal Data to third parties only where the third party (a) has
provided satisfactory assurances that it will protect Personal Data consistent with this Privacy
Policy; or (b) has signed an agreement with CFI regarding the transfer of Personal Data in
accordance with the Data Protection Directive; or (c) is located in the European Union or
another country which is deemed to provide adequate protection of Personal Data under the
Data Protection Directive;
Security
CFI has implemented technological and organizational measures to safeguard your Personal
Data from unauthorized or improper access during collection and while it is in our possession.
Sensitive information (such as gender, ethnicity, and financial information) is subject to
heightened security measures. You should also take measures to safeguard your Personal
Data by maintaining the confidentiality of your username and password, logging out of CFI’s
websites, closing your web browsers when You have concluded your online activities, and not
providing your Personal Data to persons that are unfamiliar to You.
CFI and You may communicate by email or chat and these communications may at times
contain Personal Information. While it is illegal to intercept or disclose the contents of email
and chat communications, these communications are not secure. We recommend that you do
not send sensitive information, such as financial information, by email or chat, and we will not
ask you to provide this information in this manner.
Your Right to Access Your Personal Data
You have the right to access your Personal Data, to correct your Personal Data if the
information that We have is erroneous, and in some cases to delete your Personal Data. You
may obtain a copy or correct or request deletion of your Personal Data by mail at info@cfi-
universal.com
We may impose reasonable restrictions on requests for access to or to correct your Personal
Data and We may charge You a reasonable fee as permitted by law for provision of your
Personal Data. If you request deletion of your data, We may not be able to provide services
to You. We are permitted to keep certain of your Personal Data in order to meet our legal,
financial, audit, and business needs, even if you request its deletion.
CFI Euro SL -Privacy Policy – Version. 1.0 – 12 May 2017

Limitation of Liability
CFI uses reasonable efforts to comply with the terms of this Privacy Policy and applicable law
regarding the processing of your Personal Data. Except as provided by applicable law, CFI shall
not be responsible for direct or indirect damages that may result from non-compliance with
this Privacy Policy.
Changes to Privacy Policy
CFI may change this Privacy Policy at any time without prior notice. All changes are effective
immediately after they are posted on CFI’s websites.
CFI Euro SL -Privacy Policy – Version. 1.0 – 12 May 2017
